Prathamesh Patil

cap10nem0.github.io/

in Prathamesh Patil

github.com/Cap10nem0

J 217-979-1272

✓pprathamesh2508@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Detail-oriented data analyst with 3 years of IT consulting experience in HR & Finance domain. Keen to apply my professional experience and academic background in Information Management to drive business strategies and enhance operational efficiencies. Open to relocation.

EXPERIENCE

Application Data Analyst, Accenture

Nov 2020 - April 2021

- Improved weekly report generation process by 12% by optimizing SQL queries and improving data retrieval efficiency
- Designed custom Informatica ETL pipeline to process 7.5M transactions monthly in collaboration with data integration team
- Identified and resolved data redundancy issues across organization, leading to a 30% reduction in data inconsistencies
- Implemented descriptive analytics to monitor and analyze dormant user accounts thereby saving \$0.3M on software licenses
- Spearheaded an automation project for client leadership to request month-end reports, reducing weekly 8 hours of developer efforts
- Validated HRIS, ERP, CRM systems to ensure data accuracy and integrity during production changes

Application Data Associate, Accenture

Oct 2018 - Oct 2020

- Generated ad hoc HR & Finance Excel reports using SQL Server and Oracle DB to reduce informed decision-making time by 15%
- Drafted and delivered project plan to develop a dashboard for monitoring real-time system disruptions across 7 departments
- Developed an interactive real-time statistical KPI dashboard using Power BI and CRM data for non-technical stakeholders
- Enhanced client's workforce performance by suggesting alternative resource allocation strategy, resulting in a 10% gain
- Revamped a critical ERP data extraction application for enterprise asset management monitoring
- Documented and maintained existing HR & Finance data knowledge base, including data dictionaries and standard operating procedures
- Participated and contributed in identifying areas for efficiency automation using Agile Methodology.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Aug 2021 - May 2023

3 0/4

Master of Science in Information Management

ister of Science in Information Management

- Coursework: Data Visualization; Marketing Analytics; Data, Statistical Models & Information; Information Modelling; Methods of Data Science; Data Warehousing & Business Intelligence; Text Mining; Programming for Analytics & Data Processing
- Course Assistantships & Certifications: MBA 561: Introduction to Business Analytics with R; MBA 542: Digital Marketing Analytics in Theory and Practice; BADM 544: Strategic Management (Business and Corporate Strategy)

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

UIAA Membership Campaign (Excel, Tableau, Python - pandas, scikit-learn)

- Implemented regression analysis on the university's alumni data, to predict the likely donors and their donation amount for UIAA
- Identified the key indicators like age, gender, income and intent of membership to target audiences to boost membership by 32%
- Set up experimental pipelines with A/B test to optimize promotional events and maximize the ROI in the long run

Effect of Covid on Boston City Service Helpline (Python - Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly)

- Performed EDA to identify trends, patterns, and insights arising on Boston Service Helpline (311) using Pandas
- Designed and created visually appealing and user-friendly visualization to convey actionable insights
- Analyzed 1.4m+ requests to find the most affected neighborhoods in Boston before & after COVID using Python

Sentiment Analysis of Science Fiction Novels(Python - Pandas, NLTK, scikit-learn)

- Conducted sentiment analysis on 6 Jules Verne novels to visualize 100 recurring words for positive, negative, and neutral sentiments
- Classified 14k reviews to extract feature sentiment and successfully classified into positive, negative and neutral using Python

Forest Cover Type Prediction(R - Dplyr, Tidyverse, randomForest, gbm, ggplot2)

- Implemented classification algorithms like RandomForest, SVM, Bagging and Boosting using R to find predominant forest type
- Performed feature engineering to reduce 55 columns to 13 columns and achieved accuracy of 93% using boosting technique

SKILLS

Core Competencies: Requirements Gathering, Statistics, Data Mining, Data Modeling, Data Analysis & Visualization, Data Reporting & Documentation, Regression Models, Machine Learning Algorithms, Market Research & Segmentation, Project Management Programming: Python (Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly, BeautifulSoup, Scikit-learn, NLTK), R, SQL, C# Tools & Framework: PyCharm, Visual Studio, Jupyter, MS Visio, GitHub, Jira, Azure DevOps, Agile Databases & BI tools: Oracle, MS SQL Server, MySQL, MS Access, MS Excel, Informatica, Talend, Tableau, Power BI